Guide to the Mack Buckley Swearingen papers,1920-1969.
Swearingen, Mack Buckley papers, 1920-1969.
- Series I. General Files
  - Sale of Library, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Reviews by MBS, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Loose Manuscripts, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Arnot - Ogden Speech (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Tulane History - Chapter I (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Chapter II (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Chapter III (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Chapter IV (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Chapter V; The Academical Department (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Chapter VI; The 1850s: The University and the City (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Chapter VII; The 1850s Medical Department (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Chapter VIII; The Civil War and Reconstruction (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Chapter IX; Recovery (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Chapter X; The Transition (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Chapter XI; William Preston Johnson (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Chapter XII; Newcomb College (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Chapter XIII; William Preston Johnson (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Chapter XIV; Administration of Edwin Alderman (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Chapter XV; Edwin Boone Craighead (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Chapter XVI; Robert Sharp (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Chapter XVII; Albert Bledsoe (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Appendix (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - John McDonogh, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Jefferson on Washington (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Shugg Analysis (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Papers on New Orleans (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Thesis Notes, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - The Mecklenburg Declaration of Independence (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Some Economic Aspects of Southern Reconstruction, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Thesis - 1st Draft, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Thesis Notes, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Revolutionary Leaders (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Loose Material, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Thesis - Proof (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Typescript, Carbon, Manuscripts of a Term Paper about Mississippi (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Poindexter Research Notes (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Poindexter (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Poindexter (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Books Paid for, 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Record of Books (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cuts of Documents (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Cuts of Maps (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Clippings - Misc., 1928-1948 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Official, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Columbia Visit, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Survey, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Official, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Official, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Official, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Book Purchase, 1944-1946 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Official, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Official, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - College Bulletins, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - College Bulletins, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - College Bulletins, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Bulletins, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - College, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Inventory - Annual, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Comptroller, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - College Bulletins, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Bulletins, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Personal, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Personal, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Personal, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Political Science Notes and Essays, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Personal, 1936-1950 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Personal, 1936-1957 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Personal, 1936-1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Personal, 1928-1940 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Envelope "George C. Swearingen" Misc., 1936 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Personal File, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Loose, 1944-1948 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Reading", 1953 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Journal Notebook, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Notes Notebook, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1935-1938 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Atlanta and More, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Tulane Controversy, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Wells, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Tulane - Official, 1936-1938 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Georgia State College for Women, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Tulane, 1935-1938 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Thompson Historiography (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oxford Tutorial Essays Documents - English (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Oxford Tutorial Essays Revolution of 1688 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - English History - Revolution of 1688 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - European History - Notes from Schevill's Lectures on the Ottoman History, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - European History - Notes on Schevill's Lecture, Europe since 1848 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Reformation - Lucas (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Knappen - Tudors (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - American Constitutional History - Notes on McLaughlin, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Renaissance - Joranson (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Oxford Tutorial Essays - English Political (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - English History - Economic (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - English History - Constitutional (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - European History - General Notes (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - English History - Terry's Lectures (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - French Revolution - Gottschalk (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - European History - Terry's Lectures (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Thompson's Lectures on Napoleon (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Oxford Political Science (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Mississippi State Tax Commission (Service Bulletins), 1935-1937 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Barnes Paper - Final - 1st Carbon (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - 5th Amendment (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hammondsport Speech (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Barnes - in progress, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Rejected Manuscripts - Harpres (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - How to Pick a Political Party (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - It's Time for a Change (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - They Hate Roosevelt - Marquis W. Childs (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Social Science Program (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Act II Scene 2 final "The Whole Person" (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Act III final "The Whole Person" (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Act I final "The Whole Person" (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Act II Scene 1 final "The Whole Person" (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "The Whole Person" mimeo of Play Critique by Alan Roberts, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Newsclippings, etc., 1953 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Data Presented for Consideration of the Middle States Association Visitation Team, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - MSA - Middle States Association, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - College, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - College, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - College - for the Record - Urban Renewal, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Convocation and Commencement, 1959-1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Elmira College Faculty Committees, 1960-1964 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Advisor File, 1961-1964 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Evening and Summer Sessions, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Notes USA Current, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - College Aims, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - AAUP, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - AAUP, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - College - Official Publications, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Professor Swearingen President's Advisory Committee, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - History 303-304, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - The Key, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Advisory Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Class Rolls and Grades, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - College - Notices, Circulars, etc., 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - College - Circulars, Mimeographs, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - College - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Student Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Millsaps Speech, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Westchester and Jersey, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Peace Corps, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Practice Teaching, 1962-1965 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Social Science Division Misc. Communiques, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Social Sciences 101-102, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Students - Correspondence with and about, Letters of Recommendation, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Social Studies 101-102 All College Committee, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Elmira College Workshop Minutes, 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - College - Official, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - College - Official, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - College - Official, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - College - Official and Misc., 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - College, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - College - Misc. Not Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - L'affaire Rowen (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Finger Lakes Center, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Statement on Honor System (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Absence Study, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - First Semester Grades All College, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Social Science Division, 1960-1962 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - College - Not Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - College, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - College - Reports, 1957-1962 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Catalog - Elmira, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Junior Year Abroad, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Junior Year Abroad Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Official - Not Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Social Studies 101, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Official - Not Correspondence III, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Official - Not Correspondence IV, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Notes - Various and Professional, 1959-1961 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Family, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - World Pressures and Local Initiative (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Graham (Memoir about William Dodd) and Correspondence with Ashby, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Dodd (Memoir about William Dodd) and Correspondence with Stephenson, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - American Historiography paper on Claude Bowers, and Letters from Bowers, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Talmadge, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Paper on Harry Elmer Barnes (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Elmira College Workshop and Minutes of Faculty Meetings, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Elmira College Social Science Division, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Map of Tarhite Adana (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Honors, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Grade Study (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Official Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - College, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - College - Not Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Book Orders, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Extra Copies - Various, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Family, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - CC Questionnaire (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Former Students, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - A Few Notes - Extra Copies (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Franklin Visit, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Honors Course, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Income Tax - Misc. Documents, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Lake Erie College, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Loose Printed Materials and E. C. Information Manual, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Travel Mementos - not Turkish, 1957-1958 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Family, 1955-1957 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Friends and Students, 1955-1957 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - AAA Bag with Travel Material (Driving Permits, Passport Photos, Andrea Doria Passenger List, etc.) Tour Guides, 1955-1957 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1955-1957 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Bills (mostly hotels) Receipts (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Invitations and Programs, Business Cards (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Reports from Turkish American Groups (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Time Magazine, Photos (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - USIS Bulletins, Associated Press Reports, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - USIS Bulletins, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Burdette Gardner Mimeos of "The Elmira College Junior Year Abroad", 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Trip to Turkey Cost Record I, 1957-1958 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Trip to Turkey Cost Record II, 1957-1958 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Turkey's Dilemma (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Diary - 2nd Journal, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Journal - June, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Journal - October, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Journal 27-36, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Journal October - November unit 26 and Interpolation, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Journal February-March units 1-9, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Journal April and May units 10-15, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Short piece on Turkey, Newspaper Article, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Loose pages from Journal unit 10, Confidential (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Inventory of Goods Taken to Turkey, 1957-1958 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - The Nation - Reapportionment, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - The Nation - Vietnam, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - The Mississippi Advocate, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Mississippi Gov. Barnett's Trail, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Mississippi Paul Johnson Election, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Mississippi Meredith, Old Miss, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Mississippi, Misc., 1962 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - The South - The Negro and Civil Rights, 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - South, Misc. Documents, 1937-1964 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - "The New South" by Paul M. Gaston (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Mississippi - The Negro and Civil Rights, 1962-1965 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - The South Mississippi, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - The Nation - Goldwater, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - The Nation - JFK, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - The Nation - Kefauver Material on Monopoly: John Blair, 1959-1962 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - The Nation - LBJ, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - The Nation - Medicare (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - The Nation - Misc., 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - None Dare Call it Treason, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Loose Material on Civil Rights, 1960-1964 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - The Nation - The Negro and Civil Rights, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Misc. Mementos, 1908-1932 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - A History of Tulane University, Preface - Ch. 5 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - A History of Tulane University, Ch. 6-9 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - A History of Tulane University, Ch. 10-13 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - A History of Tulane University, Ch. 14-End (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Mary, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Mary, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Mary, 1933-1953 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Letters - Bethany, Mother, Mary, etc., 1933-1953 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - G. C. Swearingen Material re: Estate, Family Genealogy, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Folder of Letters from Royal Henderson Snow, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Papers from Exeter, Oxford, 1925-1929 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - "Spirit of 1948" Senior Year Bulletin, Elmira College, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Business Papers (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Mementos - General (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Students, Others (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Letters from Students, Friends, Others (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Letters - Parents (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Letters - Parents (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Letters from Son (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Letters - Parents/Sister (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Letters - Family - Mother/Sister (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Letters - Family - Mother/Sister (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Letters from Family (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Letters from Family (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Letters from Mother (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Mother/Father (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Mother (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Letters from Mother (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Mother (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Mother (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Father (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Father (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Sister (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Sister (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Letters from Sister (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Wife (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - "The Purple and White" (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Personal, 1941-1942 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dictionary of American History, 1938-1940 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Chicago Alumni, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Policy, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Social Research Conference, 1939-1940 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Southern Historical Association, 1937-1940 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Personal, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Disaster Committee (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - P.E.L. Workers' Education, 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Personal - Misc., 1935-1938 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - E. J. Case, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Envelope of Misc. Items, 1953-1954 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Letters from MBS to Lin, 1919-1954 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Elmira College Thespis, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Letters (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Letters - Other (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Letters - Other (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Letters to Mrs. G. C. Swearingen (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Letters from Martha Dodd (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Tulane Fight, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Tulane Fight, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Official Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Official Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - J. Longino, 1918-1919 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - M. Raines, F. Mitch, G. Mills, 1922-1923 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Official Correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Jack, Hamilton, Webb, Ramsdell, etc., 1923-1927 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Family Correspondence, 1923-1924 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1927 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1927 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - M. Dodd, 1924-1928 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - M. Dodd, 1924-1928 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Martha Dodd, 1924-1927 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - R. Snow, 1925-1928 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Including Largents, 1928-1929 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Family Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Family Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Family Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - A. Wilson Family, 1934-1940 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Printing Block (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Family, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1918-1924 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Mother and Sister, 1924 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Mother and Sister, 1925 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Mother and Sister, 1926-1927 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - W. Feliciana, LA, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Drafts of "The Tulane University of Louisiana" MBS and Sam Lang, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - "The Tulane University of Louisiana", 1938 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Official Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Elmira College - Misc., Salaries, 1944-1966 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Florida SS Large Maps, 1949-1955 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Turkey - Rockefeller, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Misc. (Murray), 1956 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - The Turkey Swindle, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Family Correspondence, 1958-1966 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Family Correspondence, 1958-1966 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Family Correspondence, 1958-1966 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Talk to Painesville -"So You've Come to College" first draft, also Correspondence, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Mother's Death, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Trust Fund Class of '62, 1962-1964 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Trust Fund Class of '62, 1962-1964 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Millsaps College Alumni Fund, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - About Mother's Legacy, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Lin's Death, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - English as She is Wrote, 1963-1968 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Vann Woodward's Letter on Civil Rights, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Robischon (Comments on "So You've Come to College"), 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Patron Saint, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Wreck (family), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Musings and Biography, 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Endorsements - Students, 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - John Blair, 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - John Blair, 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Speeches and Comments/Awards and Comments, 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Elmira College - Tenure, Honor System, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Students - Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Students - Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Worship Service, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - LEC - Negotiating and Moving; Contract, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - College - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Millsaps Citation, Misc. P and W, Programs, Tickets, etc., 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - General Studies Lecture - The Social Studies - Lake Erie College, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - C. Victor Brown, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Linda's (Newman) Letters, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - E. B. White Letter (From Cornell Archives), 1937 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Slavery and the Civil War, also Hathaway (from Cornell Archives), 1852-1863 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - War of 1812 (from Cornell Archives) (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Letter from a Yankee in Mobile (from Cornell Archives), 1859 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - MBS Clippings, 1921-1967 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Castle Murder, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Feliciana, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - The Negro in the South, 1930-1939 (Box 20, Folder 16)